It's usually best to find missing data first if you can.
如果可以的话 最好先找出缺失数据
In other words, completeness issues,
也就是说 先处理完整性问题
which is a part of data quality.
这是数据质量的一部分
Sometimes you can't though, and that's fine.
有时候你找不出来 那也没事
But if you can find that missing data,
但如果你能找出缺失的那部分数据
concatenate, join, impute, whatever.
无论你是拼接、合并还是填充都好
Get it all intact there so the subsequent cleaning operations you
把缺失的数据放回去
perform on those columns or rows won't have to be redone i.e.
这样你接下来要对那些行或列进行的清理操作才不用重头来过
not filling in the missing data,
也就是说 如果不把数据缺失的地方填补完整
then cleaning some rows and columns with missing data,
就直接清理那些缺失数据的行或列
then joining that missing data in later and having to redo those cleaning operations.
之后一旦把缺失的数据放回去 你就又得把这些清理操作重新做一遍
So for our clinical trial dataset here,
来看我们的临床试验数据集
we identified three completeness issues.
我们找出了三个完整性问题
Two in the treatments table,
两个在治疗表里
the missing HbA1c changes,
HbA1c 变化缺失
and the missing records having 280 instead of 350,
还有记录缺失 本来该是 350 条的 可这里只有 280 条
displayed here in the visual assessment.
视觉评估把这些都体现出来了
Then one missing data issue in the patients table,
还有一处数据缺失是在患者表中
the missing demographic information all displayed here
即人口统计信息缺失 全在这里了
through the.isnull method on the patient's address column.
我对患者表的地址列用了 .isnull 方法
Address, city, state, zip code, country, and contact.
少了地址、城市、州、邮编、国家以及联系方式
Contact being phone number and email address.
联系方式即电话号码和电子邮箱
So we can't address this third issue,
所以第三个问题我们无法解决
the missing demographic information.
即人口统计信息缺失问题
Sometimes you just can't, you're stuck.
有时候你就是无计可施 你卡住了
We really have no way of getting this information from these people.
我们完全没办法从这些人那里获取这些信息
Because we don't know where they live,
因为我们不知道他们住在哪里
their phone number, or their e-mail address.
也不知道他们的电话号码或邮箱地址
We can't contact them.
我们无法联系他们
We could skim the phone book or the internet for their contact information,
或许我们可以查阅电话簿或上网找他们的联系方式
but it's probably most efficient to hold off until they come back
不过可能最有效的办法还是放一放 等他们回来
into our office or the hospital for example.
比如回到我们的办公室或医院
We can clean the other two issues though,
不过我们可以解决另外两个问题
the two in the treatments table.
也就是治疗表里的那两个
Missing HbA1c changes and the missing records,
即 HbA1c 变化信息缺失和记录缺失
280 instead of 350. Let's get to those now.
记录本该是 350 条而非 280 条 我们动手操作吧